There's a lot of hype around it right
now. Skills, first of all, this isn't
actually a new thing at all. Cursor
rules, I can't even remember when that
came out. Claude skills, again,
something that's been around.
>> So skills are basically a standard unit
of context to provide to agents that
teaches them to do something. So to
acquire a skill, sad reality that people
are copying skills all over. They're
designed to be reusable and yet we kind
of copy and duplicate them and copy
everywhere. So that's not awesome. When
we think about adding skills as a first
class citizen into our organizational
process, what do we need to consider?
>> You have to think about how do you own
them longterm. You're better served by
thinking of skills not as a markdown
file but as a unit of software. You have
to think about how do we maintain those
skills? How do we keep them up to date?
And so kind of the whole life cycle
management of it
>> really exciting that Tesla last week
released support for skills. There is
coverage and functionality for
evaluating skills, distributing skills
through a package manager style
mechanism and also support for skills in
a more complete life cycle way.
>> And there's all of those combined to
just create this flywheel and now
there's huge excitement over something
that we've believed all along here at
Tesla which is context should be
reusable and there's a difference
between intelligence and knowledge.
[music]
Before we jump into this episode, I
wanted to let you know that this podcast
is for developers building with AI at
the core. So whether that's exploring
the latest tools, the workflows, or the
best practices, this podcast's for you.
A really quick ask, 90% of people who
are listening to this haven't yet
subscribed. So if this content has
helped you build smarter, hit that
subscribe button and maybe a like. All
right, back to the episode. Hello and
welcome to another episode of the AI
Native Dev Podcast. My name is Simon
Maple. I'm your co-host for the for the
episode. And joining me
>> is Guy Pjani. I'm uh also co-hosting
here, CEO and founder of Tesl.
Wonderful. And today is going to be a
nice special episode where we're going
to talk about something which is there's
a lot of hype around it right now.
Skills uh agent skills just general uh
skills that we're going to be talking
about. What is a skill? How should they
be used? When should they be used? Uh
what is a skill compared to other types
of context that an agent might may or
may not use? Um, and also what are the
certain things that we want to that we
need to do to make sure a skill is
right, a skill is good, a skill is
accurate. Uh, and also some sneak peeks
into some of the, uh, some of the great
things that Tesla announced last week on
our support for agent skills and skills
generally. So, there's a lot to pack
into this episode, guy. Let's get
started.
>> Yeah, lots and lots to talk about and
skills are they're all the rage.
>> Absolutely. So, why don't we just start
why don't we just define what what is a
skill guy? Yeah, I think that's sort of
an interesting question coming from you.
It's like I sort of thought that you're
sort of a skillful person.
>> No, I'm I'm a highly skilled person, but
I struggle to define it. Lots of people
find it hard to put their finger on it.
What is maybe you learn something?
[laughter] Yeah. No. So, uh skills are
basically a standard unit of context to
provide to agents uh that teaches them
to do something. So to acquire a skill
um they have initially been introduced
by Claude as part of sort of you know
Claude skills capability. uh although
they were very very very similar to
things like cursor rules or or other
kind of a built-in guidance uh that that
existed in other agents before um but
still claude skills kind of paved the
path to definitely this as a content uh
and effectively it's just a standard
file structure that defines a skill.md
file that has some definitions of you
know what this does and some metadata
but when should the agent use it uh
alongside with supporting files designed
in a certain way so that the agent can
kind of acquire that skill, use it and
and do so in a in an LLM wise way. For
instance, a core element is this
progressive disclosure of having uh sort
of bits of knowledge that the agent can
traverse through so it's loading the
right information at the right time and
doesn't overload the context window.
>> Yeah, a couple of interesting things
that you said there. First of all, this
isn't actually a new thing at all. You
mentioned cursor rules. I can't even
remember when that came out. That was
that was a while while ago. uh uh Claude
Skills again something that's been
around for for a little while since
>> September I think September. So it's
interesting that it's kind of like you
know heating up right now. Uh another
another thing that kind of really
interested me there is when you talk
about the skills MD it's just plain text
again. We're just talking about you know
you're passing some text to um to an
agent that an LLM reads that text and
then does things based on that. Um, so
there's a lot really in terms of us
being skillful as well about how we
construct that, how we write that and
and I think we'll talk a little bit
about evals. So why have skills all of a
sudden become an overnight success and
everyone's talking about it and
everyone's releasing various skill
support. What what's happened?
>> Well, the the key thing that happened is
similar maybe to MCP is that it's become
a standard. So Anthropic very late last
year uh have kind of introduced an open
standard. Standard is a bit of a funny
term. they've kind of you know coined
one uh they called agent skills and they
published the the definition of it uh
and a little bit similar to what we've
seen with MCP the rest of the ind
industry lined up actually fairly fairly
quickly and so now within a short span
of time maybe within a month you've seen
comments from cursor and codeex and uh
uh I think Gemini and others about
supporting uh skills themselves uh and
what that does is it suddenly gives the
users the creators anybody that's, you
know, actually kind of looking to use
agents gives them an ability to create
one thing, the agent skill, uh, and roll
that out. Uh, and so you've seen at the
beginning of the year, you've seen
cursor make statements that they, uh,
will embrace skills and actually phase
out rules. Again, they're very similar
in in many of their traits. So, they
will phase that out. Uh, and you've seen
kind of this explosion of uh, uh, of
ecosystem. The other very smart thing
that uh that uh Anthropic has done is
that they created a create skill skill
that uh just made it very easy for
people to start accumulating it. Uh and
maybe last important thing is that uh
skills actually were initially
introduced in claude less as a
development thing and more as an ability
to to create some instruction for
non-developers when you're when you're
using Claude to whatever create an Excel
sheet, right? or you know perform some
type of a of a musical review, right?
And so now uh uh like that that uh that
approach is true for the sort of the
skills in agent skills as a whole. And
so it also introduced um kind of a lot
of non-developers to kind of this
opportunity of creating kind of reusable
artifacts uh that they can share across
the team. That has been very very
exciting or like reusable workflow. a
little bit of a taste of software
development style capabilities of reuse
to the non-dev world and all of those
combined to just create this flywheel
and now there's huge excitements over
something that we've believed all along
here at Tesla which is context should be
reusable it should be you know something
that uh you don't you don't want to
reinvent the wheel you know and there's
a difference between intelligence and
knowledge
>> yeah oh absolutely yeah good nice nice
little uh nice little takeaway there and
I think so let's go into a couple of
things there first of all I've actually
been doing a little bit of work with
some of the folks at codeguard. Uh and
and it's a it's a uh an amount of
context which is talking about how you
can actually build how you can review
code uh in in the most secure way
following very specific uh security uh
rules. And I think one of the
interesting things or one of the one of
the things that they saw as a big
drawback was the fact that if they want
to produce this they know that the
people who are consuming it some are
going to be using Windsor, some are
going to be using cursor, some are going
to be using claude. And so they actually
need to structure it in multiple ways so
that every different agent can consume
it. And I think this this creating this
standard that all agents can kind of
like build from allows you to
effectively be able to deliver one thing
that fingers crossed hopefully as long
as everyone starts supporting it that
people can then just kind of pull into.
I think that's a really important piece.
Um let's talk a little bit about context
and context engineering and where skills
sit in that because really skills are
you know they're a part of overall
context engineering. What would you say
are the differences between uh skills
specifically and general context that an
agent or or an LLM can use?
>> Definitely there are many uh ways to
basically introduce
more words into the context window of
the agent. You know we need to remember
that agents eventually still remain you
know just interfaces to the LLMs. So
every time the there's a request to the
LLM and the question is what what is the
data right? what is what are the tokens
that get put into that? Uh and and so
all of these different means of context
engineering, they're just about giving
the right sort of path to choosing the
right words to include in the message.
Uh so in that sense, they're all they're
all a zero- sum game, right? Of what do
you put in? Uh and you can easily put,
you know, too many things into the
context window uh that you know, if you
have so much context, you know, so much
like set the groundwork that the actual
instruction gets lost uh or too few
things so things don't get known. So all
of that is is the sort of the constant
exercise. Uh when you're talking about
external context that you provide, I'd
say there are sort of three primary
buckets. There are rules which you kind
of shove it into the context window
whether you like it or not, right? By
hell or high water. Uh you would put it
into that cloud MD or into a must rule
uh uh a mustuse rule in cursor although
cursor sometimes ignores them. Uh and
those are are mandated. You know they
are very important things but they they
take up context window space. You can't
put full-on documents. That's why you're
expensive.
>> You got to be quite careful the amount
of context you add in that because that
you can kind of bloat the context window
if you just try and put as much context
into a mandatory uh you know way that an
agent has to then read all of that. It
has limited context.
>> Exactly. So, so it's the most forceful
way to guide an agent, but you have to
be limited in content. Often times they
are an initial instruction and some
link, some pointer to another location.
Uh then you've got skills. Skills
include like cursor rules uh basically a
tiny rule like a little bit of data that
goes into the context window for the
agent to choose to invoke a skill
implicitly. You can choose to call a
skill actively like a command uh in
which case you don't need those things
there. But you can also uh uh uh you
expect the agent to invoke the skill at
the relevant time. So you have to put a
little bit of that breadcrumb in the
window. There's some development right
now, but maybe separating that out with
in the agents. Does it go and consult
some directory for now? That's the
reality. And then you've got docs. Docs
are uh just available information for
the agent to find uh but they're not
naturally findable for the agent. And so
you need to either leave a breadcrumb
somewhere like with a rule uh or you
just need to name them in a way that
allows for uh you know gps and sort of
other agentic search to find them. uh
but they purely loaded on demand and
they don't have any price to pay. So you
can have as many docs as you want. If
you have a thousand skills loaded, you
might really your agent today.
Uh but if you have a thousand docs,
they're just available. It's more about
which docs that is load at the right
time and can it actually find them. So
these are the three types we have today.
I'm sure we will have more types over
time. Again, all coming down to kind of
reusable context so that the agent
doesn't need to infer everything from
intelligence every time.
>> Yeah. And I think the interesting thing
there is something that we call
activation. I'm sure many others kind of
refer to as well which is and this kind
of like leans on to back in the MCP I
say back in the MCP days like it was 30
years ago but when we were creating MCP
servers whereby you need to be very
clear in the name of the tools the the
descriptions there so that the agent
would use them at the right times. It's
very very similar when we when we when
we talk about those various skills. You
need to be very clear in the tools in
the skill name and in the in the in the
skill description so that it doesn't
just try to do things by itself just
because it can. It needs to use those
skills at the appropriate times and just
try and do things its own way. So so I
think those are very very important
>> and it's a good time to remember as well
that while it's a standard format, they
are not standard models. Uh and so the
same instruction in the skill text right
now would be loaded by different agents
by different models. Uh although we know
in like for a fact we have like
repeating data to show that the same
words would not trigger you know haiku
and set and opus to the same action. You
know opus is much more of a kind of
smartass right and sort of can can
choose to say no I know better and won't
do it. you know, oh might need more sort
of detailed instructions and so at the
moment skills don't really
>> solve for that. They are one standard
unit of context but it's not sure that
the same words will affect uh will be
the optimal ones for different agents.
So so I'd sort of say you know think of
skills as an amazing new capability. It
is absolutely worth leaning into. We're
doing that in Tessle. We think they're
amazing. They are maybe the most sort of
standard way right now to reuse context.
But like MCP, I think they're also a
piece of the puzzle and there will be
all sorts of of sort of tools or just
sort of helpers that we would want to
reuse for making agents successful.
>> That's really interesting. So, so
essentially the standard allows it
provides a kind of standard bolt fitting
in the sense that you can integrate it
with the agents, but your mileage may
vary depending on which agent you use
because it will use it'll it'll assess
the wording and it'll it'll use them uh
differently depending on how of course
they are implemented in the background.
So that's that's a that's a good insight
as well.
>> Okay. So skills uh we can use them as
indie developers, as hobbyists, as open
source developers. Uh we can also use it
as in an organization uh to describe how
we want to do certain things in in our
certain methodologies in our certain
processes that are key to our
organizational uh requirements. Now when
we think about adding skills as a first
class citizen into our into our
organizational process, our development
process, um what do we need to consider
when building owning those skills and
actually distributing it and expecting
other you know professional developers
in our organization to to to make the
best use of that? What do we need to
consider?
>> Yeah. So I think it's a good question
and I think kind of allure of uh of
skills is that they they have this
immediate impact on it. you create some
static markdown file, you do it with a
create skill, very very low lift. Uh,
and it helps like right now you
immediately can anecdotally see that it
works. But I think just like with
software, there are differences between
kind of a one-time it worked and
therefore it's awesome uh and something
that is a sort of longived uh assets
that you now need to live with. These
are competencies that you want to reuse
across the team. So I think to to kind
of take skills to a professional level,
to a team level, to an organization
level, uh you're you're better served by
thinking of skills not as a markdown
file, but as a unit of software. This is
a a competency, a reusable competency
that you want the agent to have. Um so
this this sort of puts a a different
lens on on what are the tools that you
need to be able to own skills, right?
And to to be able to operate them and
collaborate them on them over time. Um
there are probably many things to handle
but I'd say the three to focus on is one
you need to be able to test skills just
like software you know you if you want
it to remain working or even just sort
of assess whether it works today you
have to think about what's correct and
then test or in the world of AI evaluate
uh against those two is uh really
thinking about how do you distribute
that software we can talk about this
more but at the moment there's a
>> uh kind of easy but you know sad reality
that people are copying skills all over.
They're designed to be reusable and yet
we kind of copy and duplicate them, copy
everywhere. We've seen that movie and we
know where that ends. So that's not
awesome. Uh and then the third is you
have to think about how do you own them
long term. You know they will fall out
of date just like any docs or anything
like that. They uh the models will
change and so you know a new model will
come along it will think it's very
smart, right? Or you would want to use
it with some sort of a cheap model or
open model. Um and so uh we have to we
have to think about how do we how do we
maintain those skills? How do we keep
them up to date? How do we uh allow a
team to collaborate when the person that
wrote them leaves the organization? And
so the kind of the whole life cycle
management of it. I think those are the
core ones to think of. So these are
three key pieces to to to to skills eval
uh uh package management capabilities
and life cycles. Now it's really
exciting that Tesla uh last week uh
released support for skills and in fact
would you believe it guy there there is
coverage and functionality for
evaluating skills uh distributing skills
through through a package manager style
mechanism and also support for for
skills in a in a more life cycle a
complete life cycle way. Can you believe
that? What what are the chances of all
three of those?
>> Thoughts become things.
>> Thoughts become things. So it's we're
really excited about that and you can go
to Tesla.io/registry /registry to learn
more and see some of those skills in
that registry.
>> It's a it's kind of a good point also to
just to give the shout outs to the
amazing Tesla team because I think this
has been built superbly and quickly on
it and couldn't be more proud of the
team for pulling together. Excited by
the capability
>> uh possibly more excited even by just
sort of the the sheer sort of uh power
that we've sort of seen in the team uh
as we put it together.
>> Yeah. Amazing. Let's go into these
three. Um let's you know learn break
them down a little bit. Let's learn
about why we need them, what they are,
and then let's talk a little bit about
what Tesla offers as part of this uh
release. Start with evals. There are a
couple of different types of evals that
we can that we can offer here. There's
review evals and uh task evals. Uh break
them down a little bit for us. Explain
what they are and then and then how does
Tesla uh fit in this uh in this
wonderful world of eval.
>> Perfect. So eval are uh generally more
most broadly a way to answer the
question of how good is my skill, right?
Is it because like you wrote some words
I mean I think you'd easily understand
that if you whatever like put in
unrelated text or you rambled on for
sort of an hour onto the LM it won't be
good. So it's easy to imagine something
terrible. Uh and so there's varieties of
just be able to have a systematic way of
being able to say you know how good is
my skill
>> and that's really important because like
when we talk about the anecdotal
approach which you kind of like
mentioned earlier in the episode uh that
that's what we rely on today which is
just isn't good enough. Imagine if we
were writing code and anecdotally this
feels like it works. Let's ship it. It's
just not good enough and we wouldn't do
it for any other piece of software that
we consider a key part of our workflow.
So why would we do that with skills?
>> And we all know people that you know
take forever to get to the point of it
maybe like I am right now. So it's like
you know when I was a child you know I
wanted this like all of that type of
context would not be very useful you
know at the end of it is like and
therefore when you get commit use you
know uppercase letters you know like
that's not very uh very useful. Um so so
those are as a whole and we might add
additional ones. Uh we do have review
evals and task evals as you mentioned.
Uh let me actually kind of read out a
little bit. Uh review evals focus on
just making sure that the skill adheres
to the best practices that anthropic has
released.
>> Agent skills are cross agent but
anthropic is clearly leading the charge
and they created a bunch of best
practices uh on their site that are uh a
kind of good guidance on how to build
it. They're saying things like uh be
concise, right? They're saying concise
is key. uh set appropriate degrees of
freedom. Um you know make sure you kind
of uh uh have the right structure for
the skill. Uh and so we the the review
evaluations on it just start by by
assessing it against those metrics. Uh
that already has kind of given us some
pretty interesting insights. Uh first of
all we've seen that if you use the
anthropic kind of create skill skill uh
it indeed uh it scores quite highly. You
know not that surprising you know this
is uh and to be frank we're using claud
to assess those on it. So, you know,
Claude when it creates uses those
instructions probably has a bunch of
that input. And so, we're seeing, you
know, great job anthropic. You know, if
you're using a skill to create skills,
you're probably going to score well on
all of these paths. Um, the other thing
that we've seen uh is maybe a bit of a a
couple of points against the anthropic,
which is they might not be using their
own create skill to build that. Uh, and
we've actually now run review uh evals
on uh several hundreds, maybe even past
a thousand of different skills. They
include a bunch of the anthropic ones
and we've seen some in which they don't
score terribly well on it. Uh I want to
uh pick a little bit on the anthropics
canvas design uh uh skill which uh I
guess as the name implies kind of helps
you design uh the canvas content. Uh and
on the content side we separate between
our scoring for the description as a
whole and for content. Uh it got fairly
low scores 27%. Uh and I just love the
pros that Claude gives you know its own
creators over here for this tile. It
says conciseness one in four extremely
verbose with extensive repetition of
concepts like craftsmanship and
masterpiece throughout. Contains
philosophical padding and redundant
explanations that Claude doesn't need.
Very straightforward there like
explaining what the design philosophy is
multiple times repeating the same
principles in different sections. Uh so
that's a good example of it. And later
on it goes to the progressive disclosure
one in four and it goes on to say
monolithic wall of text with no
references to external files for
detailed guidance and so on and so
forth.
>> I'm glad it's I'm glad it's Claude
slamming anthropone
in the family and I'm sure this is a
mission but I think what this goes to
show is is not at all a lack of skill
kind of in in anthropic and and you know
from the creators of canvas design. It's
just the need for for tooling, right? It
needs to be automated. uh and you know
it's possible that this was initially
created with you know say you know the
create skill maybe it predates create
skill uh and then you know over time
didn't get maintained. So anyways the
review evaluations are about that
they're about keeping you uh well
structured and say how are you applying
the best practices.
>> Mhm.
>> So that's review evals. Uh the task
evals uh go a step further and they
actually create scenarios that you would
run the agent against and see how well
it did. Uh this is actually another one
of the best practices that Anthropic
recommends. It says create uh the
evaluation scenarios ahead of actually
creating the skill like make sure you
know what good looks like uh and capture
those. But few people actually do it. It
requires more effort on it. And so we uh
create we we have done this for tiles
already. We talked about that in some
previous episodes uh for our
documentation tiles. We create a bunch
of context but we create some coding
scenarios and we run them with and
without that documentation to make sure
the documentation is good. uh we do the
same for skills. I will say task eval
for skills are more of a work in
progress. There's uh interesting
questions about how do you best extract
the evaluation scenarios out of the
skill without leaking too much of the
guidance itself into the task. Yes.
>> Uh and so there's some work there. So
I'll share a couple of anecdotes of
examples here but uh
>> take them with a grain of salt. Uh we've
seen maybe I've got like two interesting
examples of those. One is we created
task evas 10 different coding scenarios
for for instance two fairly similar
skills. One is called agent browser from
versel and we've seen that the skill was
dramatically impactful. It took the
success rate of the agent as it tries to
implement that uh from about 28% to 71%
in success. So very very significant
boost. The skill is very valuable for
agent browser. Uh and we saw another
skill called browser use uh which
conceptually is similar about the use of
browsers within agents. Uh and with that
one we saw that the baseline average was
85% and in fact using the skill was
minimally negative if they dropped that
by about three percentage points. And
again a lot of grains of salt maybe we
don't have the right tasks for it but
it's a good demonstration of maybe this
skill is not very helpful. And we've
seen a few of those examples. We've seen
cases where uh for instance some of the
anthropic skills were not bad but we're
just not very helpful because we're just
describing things the model already
knows how to do which once again comes
back to these right now are evaluations
with set maybe haiku needs it maybe opus
doesn't need it and and you want to
build those out um I'll have one more uh
interesting anecdote which is uh someone
codified karpathy's uh summary of like
the best practices that he recommends
for skills on it someone put it together
into a into a skill and published it and
we ran through it and we actually found
that it had again a minimally negative
uh effect on uh on agents. It it it we
created 10 scenarios. So it did very
well in some scenarios and worse in
others. You know one example where it
did the worst for instance is that it
just over complicated or overengineered
a simple CSV related task. Um so all of
those are I think great indications to
to to say like you need to know these
answers like you need to know whether
your skill works or doesn't and you need
to define what are the scenarios that
simulate it and then you need to be able
to test that over time as your skill
evolves and as uh the models evolve or
you're using other agents etc. There are
so many juicy takeaways in this. Like if
you are a consumer of a skill, it's
really important to know this data so
that you can understand the impact that
the skills that you're pulling in is
going to make to your agent uh
experience.
>> The second piece is as a producer of
that skill, as as the owner or creator
of that skill, it's it's no it's no use
just creating a skill and assuming again
through through anecdotal evidence
saying, "Yeah, this feels like it's
working better." You need to
particularly with the scenarios, it's
important to say, "Hey, you know what?
This is making my experience. this is
this is going to make my chances of
doing this thing the way I want it to to
be done three times four times more
likely to happen. But I think the key
thing here is when you mention the
scenarios. So if you have an eval where
it runs across 10 scenarios, you can see
what it's good at, what it's not good
at, and that provides you with the
insight to say these pieces these these
scenarios working really well. I'm going
to leave that description. These are the
pieces I need to change. So from a
producer point of view, from the creator
and the owner of that skill, they can
actually create the best skill. from the
consumer of the skill they can then say
right all these skills are available I'm
going to pick these ones because I feel
like they're going to be you know they
are showing the data is showing me that
these going to actually make it more
impactful of course then everyone's
environment is different it's there is
going to be somewhat an anecdotal yes
this is actually working well or it's
not working well but I think this gives
us like the start we need
>> the second piece which really that you
mentioned that I think is is so
important
>> is as models change and and that
variation across models or agents
There is going to be variety across you
know the the environments as I say but
even if something works for a model in
my agent today as that model grows as
the training data changes my context
needs to change as well my my skills
need to be updated potentially
>> if it relies upon things that are in old
training data or new training data they
will act differently and we need to use
maybe even different uh levels of the
same skill based on the agent I'm using
or the the model I'm using. So these are
these are kind of important
considerations that we as users and
creators of skills need to constantly be
thinking about.
>> Absolutely. And I will sort of say that
uh there's a similar analogy to um uh to
tests in uh kind of real world scenarios
right which is you know works on my
machine you know versus uh versus
something else is very much uh a real
risk with skills as well. uh as well as
you know developers don't like writing
tests you know you uh and some some love
writing tests but you know many do not
uh and so people avoid this sort of hard
question of what is correct and you know
at at Tesla we will help you generate
things we'll we'll help you build those
out but over time the the definition of
what is correct and what this skill
should do is actually more important
than the words that you use because the
words themselves they will change from
environment to environment from model to
model uh uh maybe over time, you know,
something that wasn't in the training
data now is. And so you can shrink it.
You can actually say less now. Maybe at
some point you don't need the skill at
all. But all of those uh uh will be
dynamic. What actually would be less
dynamic is what do you want uh the
result to to be that one you need to
evolve it when your actual requirements
change, your systems change and you need
to call an API differently or you know
your sort of business goals have
changed. Um, but I think not only are
these evaluations critical for you to be
able to make the most out of agents
today and and be able to not regress
over time,
>> the definition of of what good looks
like is actually more important than the
context itself.
>> Yeah. And I think the other thing that
intrigued me with with what you were
saying is how essentially we're trying
to create a set of questions from an
answer that we already have. We have a
skill that defines the way we want to do
things. What we're trying to extract
from that is, oh, okay, you're trying to
do this. You've got this end goal.
>> What I want to do is create a set of
scenarios whereby
uh we're not trying to feed or guide an
agent into hitting that end goal as we
would want it, but more what is the
general way that people would try and
get to such a goal, such an end point,
and then will it do it in the way that
the skill is trying to? So it's very
hard to try and pull the question out of
the answer almost and eval a good eval
just like a good test
>> they're hard to do well and I think it's
important that you know we rely upon
that good framework and that's what of
course the team is the AI engineering
team at Tesla and others are working on
>> and it's a I think it's an important
note uh that you know right now again
this is all journey and at the moment we
are talking about creating evaluation
scenarios for public skills which are
not ours and with limited information
because we just have the skill um when
we generate for instance documentation
we have so much more info we have the
code itself we have potentially other
callers so there's a lot more
information to extract correctness um
but the true uh uh kind of correct
evaluation scenarios come and and that's
what we do in Tesla when we sort of
engage more with a full-on customer it
comes when we actually get to kind of
inspect reality up front you can extract
a lot of that knowledge out of git
history and what have been the actions
and over time you can extract a lot of
learning from uh agent logs and how we
build. Um and so all of those are
correct when you're when you are an
organization, you're creating skills for
yourself. You're trying to you know
optimize and tune them on an ongoing
basis and so you get that sort of
feedback data uh from uh from actual
agent users of it. It's a little bit
harder to do it for kind of third-party
skills that we consume and and we do
hope just like with documentation, we
today are creating evaluations for
someone else's skills, but we encourage
and would love the owners of those
skills to come to us and we will pass
those evaluations and the ownership of
the eval scenarios to those people so
they can, you know, kind of tune them
and correct them and then we'll just,
you know, run the evals and publish
them.
>> I love it. And um just clicking around
actually on the Tesla.io /registry where
you can see the tiles and the skills and
there are a bunch of featured tiles but
also then you see the top performing
skills and tiles and what's great is you
can see you know I can click through and
I can see the skills and I can see the
eval results on various skills uh as
well with different scenarios that I can
click you know I can I can open up the
scenarios I can see what the scenario is
doing and I can see the kind of like you
know the the the with and without the
skill with and without test and you can
see what it's good at and what it's not
>> and if you dig in a little bit you'll
also see some of the pros uh you see
some of the sort the uh the text that
Claude writes as it uh as it assesses it
uh yes it's entertaining and that's
reason enough to keep it on the website
uh but it actually has some very
concrete advice uh to say hey this is
the problem you know like that
monolithic wall of text comment was you
know entertaining but it's also uh very
clear guidance to the owner of that
skill to say hey you should break this
up
>> we should totally have like modes of how
we want Claude to give us that
information so if it's if it's if it's
saying okay this is how this is the
review eval you can get it to be nice to
me. I'm I'm I'm fragile. Be nice to me.
You can get it to
>> a little bit of a I'm in a tough spot
right now.
>> Well, I think the the other way is like
the the glimmer of hope. So, like there
will shortly, you know, we do this uh
with customers today. There will be an
optimize button next to it. This is like
>> hold out hope, you know, we have this.
Do you want us to fix this for you?
Nice.
>> Click this button and we'll create a new
version of it. So,
>> which is what LLMs and things like that
are good at as It doesn't mean and
that's it comes back to you know you
need to define the evaluation that is
correct because if we if we generate you
know documentation with an LLM and we
generate evaluation with an LLM and the
two are misaligned you have to choose
who do you believe
>> and what we want to believe is the
evaluation but we need the owner to
bless that uh once they do it's actually
you know not that complicated to create
a genetic pipelines to optimize the
context to achieve the goal
>> we covered eval quite a lot there I EV
valid is actually a really important
piece though. So I'm I'm really pleased
we kind of went into depth on that. The
two other places that the two other
pieces that you mentioned, package
management uh or package manager
capabilities and also the life cycle of
skills. Let's talk about those. Starting
off with package manager.
>> Yeah. So I think um there's more of a
technical element to it, but it really
comes out of thinking about skills as
software, not as documentation. Um so
today when you want to install a skill
first you your option was to just sort
of go off and copy it you know from
wherever it is that you want or you
created a skill put it somewhere so your
team can do it and remember that skills
are are designed to be a reusable entity
so really the core element to them is
spread them to your team and uh so
that's inconvenient uh we've seen you
know a really handy tool from Versel
called skills.sh Sage and so today you
see you know within a week it took it up
and people do you know npx skills I and
you know provide a GitHub repo and what
it does is it copies something from a
GitHub repo to theirsklls folder uh and
now they uh kind of commit it to their
repo right and they duplicate it and
what happens if the GitHub repo got an
update well they're none the wiser they
don't get that uh we've even seen worse
than that we've seen the fact that you
know because uh uh people install skills
but then maybe other people in the team
are using different agents They might
even duplicate that skill into both the
dotcloud/sklls and the dotcursor that's
skills. We're seeing an entertaining uh
effect of all these different agents
going and reading skills out of
dotcloud/sklls. Yeah,
>> it's really it's a mess and that is just
not kind of a good recipe for a for a
happy future. You know, we um
>> we will uh we need something better and
this is a problem that we've already
solved in software. You know, we we know
how to handle reuse in software. Uh we
call it a package manager, right? Or a
dependency system. uh and it requires a
few things. It requires uh first of all
like some form of manifest file that
knows what you've downloaded. Actually
even before that you need uh whatever
piece of content that you have to have a
version to have an identifier to say
well this is this is the thing that I've
downloaded and maybe sever style
indication of of the delta and ordering
of those versions. Um once you have a
manifest file with those skills that you
have, you should be able to run an
update, run an install, uh maybe add
some other criteria, separate ones from
different environments like dev and
production. So all of those things are
are solved problems. They uh they you
know we have a lot of practices that we
can bring to four to to make them work
well. Uh we also know that uh pretty
much every uh programming language has
its own dependency system because each
of them have some subtle important
differences in how you want to handle
the dependency relationships and
installations and environments. Um and
so what we need is we need a a package
manager for skills and I will sort of
say skills and context because as we
mentioned skills is is not the only type
of context. Uh and that's basically what
we're building in Tessle. know we've had
the Tesla registry for a long time. It's
always been the sort of concept of you
know this is this is a context that is
version that is consumable in a way that
is you know like a professional uh
software development team uh uh tool uh
and now today we you know we extended
that to uh to skills uh which is really
really exciting. So it allows you to u
uh tessle skill install whatever skill
that you want. you know, we're not going
to get in your way if you just want to
download something off a repo. But, you
know, without any further effort, we
will remember that you downloaded that,
you know, from in in a manifest file and
we'll allow you to update it over time.
Uh, we will install it to whatever agent
that you want and by default, we will
still commit it to your repo. So, we
don't get in the way. Maybe other team
members have not installed Tesla yet.
But we think the right destination for
you is to uh change that mode and stop
vendoring those dependencies. Stop like
committing them and duplicating them and
having just the manifest file. And just
like you npm install or whatever your
equivalent is uh in your repo, you also
Tesla install or Tesla skill install if
it's just the skills that you want and
it will uh uh put them in the right
agent for the right uh uh for the right
user for what they're using. And so we
generally, you know, believe and again
it doesn't feel like a complicated or
sort of a harsh statement is that, you
know, skills uh just sort of need a
better distribution system.
>> Yeah. And and I love the two differences
there. Uh obviously like you know what
we talked about with some solutions is
is more of a directory. I guess it
doesn't necessarily uh host various
skills. It more points to other skills.
There are benefits and and and drawbacks
to that to that approach. Uh I think
when you have something more like a
traditional package manager where it
kind of hosts that content, it can do it
can it can look after a bunch of those
things in a bunch of things for that
content including the versioning and so
forth. Um in including the manifest that
says these are the things that I want to
use. Um, so I think I think that ability
to say, okay, if I want to, you know,
push something to Tesla, publish a skill
to tessle, I can have all of that cool
stuff, including things like eval,
including things like the versioning and
things like that. However, if I just
want to use it lightly, I could actually
say, I want to point to this GitHub
repo. I don't want to necessarily do,
you know, publish anything or or own
anything within within the test
registry. Um, and and so that will still
happen. We'll still we'll still add that
to manifest, but of course, there will
be a few little drawbacks. We wouldn't
have the eval. We wouldn't have things
like the ability to to pick a version
because it's just there on GitHub. It's
not necessarily a version in a registry.
So, we can't we couldn't identify. So,
we more points to the to the latest. But
these Yeah, I think these are really
really important things when we think
about skills as a first class citizen in
a developer workflow. These are the
capabilities that we need to to to do
professional development to do you know
auditing as well. What what skill did I
use to create these types of things?
Well, you actually have a look at your
manifest and you can say, well, this was
this was the skills I used. These are
the processes.
>> And I think I don't want to diss the
existing capabilities. I mean,
JavaScript thrived before npm. You know,
Java thrived before Maven. It's not
they're not necessary to be able to
provide value, but just at the pace that
everything is happening right now,
>> uh I I think I think we need to move
quickly.
>> Yeah.
>> With this as well. And over time also uh
it's fair to expect uh Tessle to
introduce other things that you have in
package managers like can we inspect
skills to see if they're malicious. Can
we uh we already run these evaluations
to sort of say you know like give the
consumer some indication to say well I'm
seeing 17 different skills are trying to
do the same. Give me some indicators to
tell me you know what which one you know
might be better for me what what worse.
And so all of those traits will will
come along learning from the past versus
trying to uh ignore it. It's absolutely
it's a it's a similar pattern to other
things that we've used. So why wouldn't
we do things in
>> hopefully a healthy ecosystem.
>> So a lot of the stuff that we've talked
about kind of from the value that a
package manager style solution offers
actually leans into a little bit of the
the requirements for what we need for
software in a life cycle. Um tell us
about what those you know what you see
the needs on a skills style approach
with uh life cycle and professional
development professional workflows as a
constraint.
>> Yeah. Uh for sure and I guess again they
all sort of stem out of the you know
once you think about skills as
innovative software kind of the list
that you need for them becomes almost
obvious. Um uh skills need to evolve. Uh
and so first of all again you need to
version them or something. You need to
commit their source material. Fine we
have that. uh but then when you
collaborate on them you need to be able
to know that a change hasn't regressed.
So that's where eval kick in. We talked
about them sufficiently you know but you
need a system that every time there is a
pull request or modification you know it
can modify it. Uh skills rarely live in
isolation. They are description of a of
a practice but often times they describe
a system or a library or even the
practice itself evolves and so you need
uh some ability to keep them fresh. So
something where every time you modify
not the skill but you modify you know an
API next to it or something else uh you
need to be able to track and know that
you need to update the skill or not and
again sort of make sure that it hasn't
regressed. Um you know those are are
sort of core like as you build it uh you
need to define it. They need a standard
sort of CD system, right? If we talked
before was sort of the git style and the
CI system, you know, you need some
element of deployment
uh to say, okay, publish this now to the
registry or committed to the relevant uh
repos if they're changing so that those
things are automated and they're not,
you know, they're not uh uh overlooked
or create manual toil. And lastly, you
have to think about observability. I
mean eval and synthetic tests are are
all good and well but uh they don't
represent production right they don't
represent uh what is deployed and so you
have to think about how do you observe
skills in production which is basically
observing agent logs and be able to
extract out of those cases where uh
where the the skill didn't work and the
the user had to either manually invoke
it or had to uh uh correct its behavior.
uh cases where failures repeated and
this might be an opportunity to create a
new skill. So all of those uh represent
the sort of full system right from from
editing and collaborating on the uh the
code of skills on it to a CI/CD system
on it to observability and closing that
loop. Uh I think you need all of those
for skills and you know our vision at
Tessle has always been that software
development will go from being
codeentric to being specentric right or
intent centric uh where what development
teams do is they collaborate on on
intent on capabilities uh on how to
build software and what it is that you
build. Uh and I think skills are a great
manifestation of that uh and so we need
the software development paradigm around
this. you know, we're going to expand
into debugging and others. So, we're
very excited about that. That's, you
know, a version of this is what we've
been building at TESL all along. And we
work with some, you know,
forwardthinking customers that are, you
know, like building and developing
context this way all along, long before
skills got introduced. Uh, and they've
been amazing and we're learning from
them. Uh and so you can expect from us,
you know, more and more capabilities uh
both self-s serve. We definitely want to
help open source skill developers be
able to maintain and do all of that with
minimal toil. Uh and of course for
organizations. So if you're you'll see
more coming on the self-serve side and
we'll sort of announce it as it comes.
Uh but if you can't wait on it, send us
a note at contacts.io.
Uh and yeah, we'd love to uh to work
with you. and you know truly excited
about kind of the point we are in the
timeline in in the sort of creation of
indeed this sort of intentric software
development paradigm.
>> Yeah, super exciting and of course if
you're interested in seeing some of the
evals using some of the skills on our
registry wanting to publish skills in
our registry head to tesla.io
and of course you can see all the data
there and of course you can start
getting involved grab the CLI and do all
the things I just said publish consume
and so forth. Yeah.
>> And uh I will note, you know, we we we'd
love feedback. We appreciate feedback.
Uh please send any uh any thoughts that
you have. Uh and we did add core
capabilities. We didn't proactively run
task evaluations on many thousands of
skills. We don't feel like we're quite
ready to do that yet. But if you see a
skill that is missing or one that you
want us to evaluate, there's an easy
button over there and we will quickly
get on it.
>> Awesome. This has been a fun
conversation on skills and I think it's
an important one for people to people to
learn right now.
>> We might eventually acquire some even.
We'll see. We'll see.
>> Look for a few in the room.
>> Let's not overpromise. Let's Let's overd
deliver. Awesome. Thank you very much,
guy. Always a pleasure. And thanks
everyone for listening. Tune in next
time.